人人影视
YYeTs.com
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译： 暴龙蛋      圈圈      阿髻
翻译： 苏小黛      Kiko      DustD      胖兔纯
时间轴： 浓子   萌    校对： 苏小黛   胖兔纯
后期： 孤帆    总监： 米小勒   胖兔纯
塞勒姆
第一季  第十一集
《塞勒姆》前情提要
Previously on Salem.
这名妓女自此被驱逐
This whore is hereby banished.
我很遗憾你心上人所遭遇的一切
I am sorry about your girl.
他已被夺取言语能力
He is rendered incapable of speech.
她将一个蜘蛛捧在肩头
She held a spider to her neck.
她好像在喂它
She seemed to feed it.
你只要告诉我一个名字
You have but to tell me a name.
她先跟我说了梅西·路易丝
And she started with Mercy Lewis.
梅西
Mercy?
我会抓住她和她的那些女孩们
I will have her and her girls.
她不在这  她下午出去了
She's not here. She went out this afternoon.
她还没回来
She's not returned.
你可以想象当我知道
You can imagine my shock
约翰·奥登上尉是塞勒姆恐怖事件的
to discover that John Alden
幕后黑手时有多惊讶
stands behind all of Salem's horror.
我宣布以巫术罪名逮捕你
I place you under arrest for witchcraft.
曾经我多希望你能是我的儿子
There was a time I wished you my own son.
那你就该知道我不是巫师
Then you know I'm no witch.
很遗憾  上尉
Sadly, captain...
你不再是我了解的那个人了
I do not know you at all anymore.
你真相信他有罪吗
Do you truly belive him guilty?
无论我相信与否  在这讨论都没有意义
Whatever I believe of John Alden is not at issue here.
所以我们才需要一场审判
This is why we have a trial.
审判约翰·奥登
A trial of John Alden.
你很吃惊吗
Does this surprise you?
你的侍女对他的指认坚定不移
Your own servant's accusations were firm and... and very clear.
除非...
Unless...
当然有这种可能
Unless, of course,
也许是你被情感蒙蔽了双眼
perhaps your own feelings cloud your judgment?
我对约翰·奥登的情意
Any feelings I once had for John Alden were extinguished
早在我嫁给乔治时就消失殆尽了
once I gave my heart to George.
但我担心的不是我的情感
But it is not my feelings that concern me.
那是谁的
Then whose?
塞勒姆的人们
Salem's.
虽然约翰·奥登是颗毒瘤  但人们崇拜他
John Alden is a firebrand, but he is adored by the commoners.
我已经听到下面人蠢蠢欲动的惊慌了
I've already heard their whispers of dismay.
你是在建议我不要把奥登送上法庭吗
Tell me...are you suggesting that I not bring Alden to trial?
不
No.
我是建议你不要孤军奋战
I am suggesting you do not fight this battle alone.
让行政委员会去决定到底要不要审判
Allow the select board to decide whether a trial is warranted.
有他们的支持  我相信他们会全力支持你
With their backing... and I assure you, you have it fully...
其他人绝不会再有异议
you will quell any dissent.
你就这么自信
And are you confident
行政委员会会投票把奥登送上法庭吗
that the board will vote to bring Alden to trial?
非常确定
As sure as I stand before you.
那好
Yes.
我去召集行政委员会开个会  谢谢你
I shall summon the board at once. Thank you.
还有  牧师
Oh, and, reverend?
梅西·路易丝那儿有消息了吗
Any luck in finding Mercy Lewis?
她也一定要接受末日的审判
She, too, must face her day of reckoning.
还没找到
Not yet.
但我很有耐心
But I'm a patient man.
她躲得了一时  躲不了一世
And a witch can't hide forever.
*擂我战鼓*
*Pound me the witch drums*
*鼓鸣震天*
*Witch drums*
*擂我战鼓*
*Pound me the witch drums*
*鼓鸣震天*
*The witch drums*
*宁入地狱*
*Better pray for hell*
*不留人间*
*Not hallelujah*
这到底是什么
What is it?
告诉我
Tell me.
你为什么要销毁它
And why you felt the need to detroy it.
告诉你什么
Tell you?
好像是你告诉我的
Was it not you who just told me
这是个神奇的瞬移面具吧
that it was a magical transporting mask?
我没说错吧
Did I get that right?
别糊弄我
Don't you dare mock me.
我给了你很多次机会  让你私下解释
I've afforded you the privacy to explain.
你还要我说多少次
Which I have done many times.
这是我旅行时买的工艺品
It is an artifact of my travels.
够了
Stop.
别再骗我了  我只想知道真相
No more lies. I simply want the truth.
这个面具的真相吗
The truth of the mask?
你的真相
The truth of you.
你到底是什么身份
Of who and what you are.
好吧
Fine.
也许有人不会嫌我问题多
Perhaps there is someone who is not yet tired of my questions,
一个熟知外面的世界
someone with knowledge of other worlds
并且不畏分享的人
who isn't afraid to share it.
英克里斯·麦哲
Increase Mather.
为什么你一定要拿这种荒唐的事儿
What on earth would you want to bother him
去麻烦人家呢
with this nonsense for?
荒唐
Nonsense?
那不如去让英克里斯鉴定一下吧
Why don't we see if Increase regards this as nonsense?
我相信他不会觉得荒唐
For I do not believe he will.
安
Anne.
Anne!
你知道我为什么要回到塞勒姆吗
Do you know why I came back to Salem?
呵呵
Lovely.
我的回答只会让你不满
More questions I can answer to your dissatisfaction.
我回来不只是为了追捕巫师
Not only to hunt witches,
更重要的是让我儿子成人
but to make a man of my son.
你抓到几个巫师
You found some witches?
那你也算不虚此行了
So your trip is not a total loss.
你真的看不见我为你铺好的路吗
Do you really not see the path that I've set you on?
那个妓女已经不在了
The whore is gone.
现在正是千载难逢的机会
A rare opportunity awaits you now
你可以在塞勒姆所有人民面前宣告自己
to announce yourself before the entire province.
宣告什么
And what is that?
明天我会将约翰·奥登的案子提交委员会
Tomorrow I shall bring John Alden's case before the board.
柯顿  你是个既有天赋又有说服力的发言人
Cotton, you are a persuasive... nay, a gifted speaker.
我希望你支持我
I want you there by my side.
我不去
I will not.
约翰·奥登是我的朋友  可能是我唯一的朋友
John Alden is my friend, perhaps my only one.
你会让友情
And you would allow friendship
阻挡你自我提升的步伐吗
to stand in the way of your own elevation?
他是无辜的
He is innocent.
你明明知道
And you know it.
我知道吗
Do I?
你又知道吗
Do you?
他就是你的酒肉朋友  突然你就能
A man shares your whiskey and suddenly you can...
就能看清他的灵魂
you can see into his very soul
证明他没被恶魔侵蚀走向黑暗了吗
and attest that it has not been blackened by the devil.
我可没有这番本事
I, myself, possess no such omniscience.
很久以前  我也面临过同样的困境
You know, long ago, I faced the same dilemma as you.
我要么跟一个我很喜欢的同学反目
It was state the case against a fellow student, a classmate,
一个我喜欢的年轻人
a young man I... I quite liked
要么缄口不语  放走一个被指控的巫师
or remain silent and allow an accused witch to walk free.
让我猜猜
And let me guess.
你眼睁睁看着他被烧死了
You watched him burn.
没有
No.
我的情感打败了理智  那个年轻人被释放了
I let my feelings intercede, and the young man was freed.
可是两年后
And two years later,
他在一次邪教仪式上把两个处女割喉了
he slit the throats of two virgins in a satanic ritual.
都怪我
My mistake.
此后我便一直心存愧疚
And it has haunted me ever since.
所以考虑好你的决定
So consider carefully your decision.
你很了解我
You know me well.
但你有多了解约翰·奥登呢
Just how well do you know John Alden?
按照你的要求  我调查了委员会成员
I surveyed the board per your request.
结果呢
And?
六位委员确定
Six of the selectmen will, indeed,
会选择让奥登受审
opt to take Alden to trial.
其余五位  念及昔日他的父亲
The other five, loyal to the memory of his father,
会投反对票
will vote for dismissal.
还有两个席位
That leaves two seats.
我会按照你的要求投票
I shall vote as you have asked.
我保证
I assure you.
那就只能由我
So this leaves me,
作为病重丈夫的代表  打破平衡僵局了
as a proxy for my ailing husband, to break the tie.
来  我们把这件事解决了
Come. Let's get this over with.
所有人民
Must we not hold all our citizens,
不论贫穷富贵
both commoner and the sons of privilege,
标准面前无一例外
to the same standard?
如若不忠  必将上颈手枷
When they cheat, must they not be pilloried?
如若偷窃  必将施以鞭刑
When they steal, must they not be whipped?
如若背弃对上帝的承诺
And when they fail to uphold their promise to God and choose,
选择与恶魔为伍
instead, to take league with the devil,
必将因此受到审判
must they not then be judged by their decision?
谢谢  牧师
Thank you, Reverend.
相信委员会已做好投票准备
I believe the board is ready to vote.
奥登上尉被指控施以巫术
Captain Alden has been accused of the practice of witchcraft.
牧师慷慨同意
The good reverend has graciously agreed
让委员会决定他是否要接受审判
to allow the board to decide whether he should go to trial.
所以  认为奥登上尉
So, those who believe
应该被当做巫师接受审判的人有谁
that captain Alden should be tried as a witch?
六人同意审判
Six for trial.
那认为奥登上尉
And those who believe
为人正直  此项指控
that captain Alden's distinguished character
毫无根据的有谁
renders such accusations baseless?
五人反对审判
Five for dismissal.
霍尔先生
Mr. Hale?
塞勒姆人民在等待你的投票
Salem awaits your vote.
反对
Dismissal.
六比六
Six to six.
也就是说决定性的一票在我手上
Which means I must break the deadlock.
我投...
And I shall cast my vote --
其实  西布里夫人
Actually, Mrs. Sibley...
你不用投票
Your vote is not required.
你肯定会很高兴
You will be pleased to learn
因为乔治的身体状况大有好转
that George's health has progressed,
至少已经可以自己行使投票权了
at least to the point where he is able to cast his own vote.
谢谢你  医生
Thank you, doctor.
牧师  是你说他被巫师控制了
Reverend, you yourself said that he was held in the witch's grip.
可能吧  也可能不是
Perhaps. Perhaps not.
他的身体状况已在稳步好转
His condition has steadily improved.
好转  他都不能说话
Improved? He cannot speak.
动也几乎不能动
He can barely move.
他就只会  吐痰
All he can do...is spit.
正是
Yes, precisely.
乔治  亲爱的老朋友
George, my dear old friend,
如果你能理解
if you can understand the words
我现在说的话  请吐一口痰
that I am speaking to you, please spit.
简直荒唐
This is ludicrous.
西布里夫人  其实一点都不荒唐
Actually, Mrs. Sibley, it is anything but.
你丈夫是委员
Your husband is a selectman
他非常想履行自己的公民义务
and he is eager to perform his civic duty.
那好  准备好了
Well, then. Sir?
现在  乔治  你告诉我  你觉得
And now, George, tell me -- do you believe that this man,
约翰·奥登应不应该接受审判
John Alden, should now stand trial?
同意还是反对
Yea or nay?
如果你表示赞成
If your answer is in the affirmative,
请吐口水
will you please spit?
把他关回牢里
Return him to the jail.
奥登上尉将接受审判
Captain Alden will stand trial
罪名为施用巫术
on the charge of witchcraft.
开门
Open it.
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
退下
Now leave us.
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
我警告过你
I warned you.
我说过留在塞勒姆  你会死的
I told you that should you stay in Salem, you would die here.
你是来提醒我的吗
So you came here to remind me?
还是来送葬
Or to bury me?
我是来道歉的
I came to apologize.
不是为了今天的投票
Not for today's vote,
而且为了我当初的选择  害你沦落至此
But for the one that I cast that sent you on this course.
要是我接受你的建议去纽约
Had I accepted your offer to go to New York,
远离这里
far from this place,
就不必理会英克里斯·麦哲的投票或是审判了
we would know nothing of votes or trials or Increase Mather.
如果我不去打仗
And if I hadn't gone to war
如果你不嫁给西布里
or you hadn't married Sibley.
我们今天的局面不是单一的选择造成的
There was no one choice that sent our course awry.
听我说
Listen to me.
如果你接受审判  他们会绞死你
If you go to trial, they will hang you.
但还有办法能逃过这一劫
But there is still a way to prevent such a fate.
如果你离开  就无法接受审判了
They cannot try you if you are not here to be tried.
越狱吗
Escape?
-你打算...  -我会安排好
- Is that what you...  - I will arrange it.
这事不容易  但只要计划周详
It won't be easy, but properly planned.
我有手段  人脉任我调遣
I have resources, means at my disposal.
-玛丽  -资源之广远超过你想象
- Mary. - Far more widespread than you might imagine.
玛丽  不要
Mary, no.
我不走
I won't go.
审判的结局只有上绞刑架
But a trial will result with you in the gallows.
你得知道
You must know this.
我一直不懂吉尔斯·科里为何不抵抗
You know, I always wondered why Giles Corey never fought back,
为何他宁可被逼至死
why he let them press him to death
也不肯认罪
rather than plead to their charges.
现在我懂了
But now I know.
他明白一旦遂了他们的心意就彻底输了
He knew he lost the moment he played their game,
就会令他们的疯狂之举显得冠冕堂皇
dignified their madness.
所以我不会从我出生的地方逃走
So, no, I won't run, not from my birthplace.
我宁愿死在这里
I'd rather die here.
你或许能如愿以偿
And so perhaps you will get your wish.
麦哲牧师
Reverend Mather?
你是霍尔家的小姐
You're the Hale girl.
安  先生
Anne, sir.
你是想跟我聊聊
Do you wish to speak to me,
还是只想观看我用餐
or are you simply content to watch me eat?
我有个问题
I have a question...
关于巫师
of witches.
可不是嘛
Indeed.
你只是好奇  还是遇见巫师了
Are you merely curious or have you encountered one?
安  你在这儿啊
Well... Anne, there you are.
打扰麦哲牧师用餐了
Interrupting Reverend Mather's dinner.
她在询问有关巫术之事
She was querying me about witchcraft.
是吗
Was she?
麦哲牧师正准备回答我的问题
Reverend Mather was about to answer my questions
而其他人都不能老实回答我
that others seem unable to answer truthfully.
也许我能提供一些帮助
Well, perhaps I can be of some assistance
好让牧师安心继续用餐
so the reverend can finish his meal in peace.
也许  但你会老实回答吗
Perhaps. But will you speak honestly?
我会的
I will.
我并不介意
Well, it is no matter to me.
治安官  霍尔小姐
Magistrate, Miss Hale.
别再说谎了
No more lies.
不再说谎了
你们有谁玩累了吗
Have either of you tired of this game?
我向你们保证  我可不累
For I assure you, I have not.
梅西比你聪明得多
Mercy's too smart for you.
我们绝不供出她的下落
We'll never tell you where she is.
你们是这么想的吗
Is that what you think?
我们在这里
That we're here together
是因为我要你们帮忙找到梅西·路易丝吗
because I require your help in locating Mercy Lewis?
不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
我来这里是出于善举
I am here as an act of charity.
善举
Charity?
帮我逮捕她  就能饶你们一命
Aid me in apprehending her and your lives will be spared.
但要是你们负隅顽抗
But if you persist in defying me,
我无从选择  唯有处死你们
I can offer you no alternative to the stake.
梅西不会让我们死的
Mercy won't let us die.
她会来救我们
She will come for us.
也许无眠长夜中这种想法能聊以慰藉
Perhaps such a thought comforts you in your sleepless night,
但我向你们保证
But I assure you,
不管你们是否帮忙  我都会找到梅西·路易丝
I will find Mercy Lewis with or without your help.
你来晚了
You're late.
我很抱歉  但我也得小心提防
Well, I'm sorry, my lady, but I have to take precautions
英克里斯还在四处找我
with Increase still searching for me.
你是对的
You're right to.
关于英克里斯  你曾经提出了一个办法
You offered a solution once for Increase,
被我否决了
one that I dismissed,
也许我当时的反应是错误的
but perhaps it was only my response which was misguided.
你是什么意思
So what are you saying?
我是说英克里斯·麦哲必须死
I'm saying that Increase Mather must die.
这件事得我们来做
And we are the ones to do it.
杀了他吗
Kill him?
为什么是现在
But why now?
他的魔爪越伸越长
The shadow he casts grows longer.
而缇图芭的指控危及到了一个我很在乎的人
And Tituba's accusations jeopardize one that I care for deeply.
约翰·奥登
John Alden?
不
No.
我亲爱的梅西
My dear, dear Mercy.
是你
You.
你从一个迷失少女成为恶魔的助手
Your path from lost girl to devil's assistant
这是我也走过的路
is one that I walked, too.
我会保护你  就像保护我自己一样
I would protect you as I would mine own self.
如今缇图芭靠出卖我们换得释放
Now, Tituba's released, rewarded for her treachery,
而你却像个野兽般被追捕着  恐惧着
And you live like an animal, hunted and fearful.
我要怎么做  何时动手
So how will I do it and when?
别急  亲爱的
Easy, my dear.
许多巫师曾试图杀死英克里斯
Many a witch has sought to claim Increase's life
最后却都丢了他们自己的小命
And lost theirs in the process.
我们的计划必须考虑周全
Our efforts must be planned...carefully.
你一定已经想到办法了吧
Surely you must have a method in mind.
没错
Yes.
的确有  把手指给我看看
I do. Show me your fingers.
手指
My fingers?
应该能行
These will do.
什么能行
For what?
袭击我
Now strike me.
小姐
My lady?
像对待敌人般撕扯我的血肉
Tear at my flesh as you would your vilest enemy.
不用怀疑你的耳朵和信仰
Do not question your ears nor your faith.
照我说的做
Do as I ask.
你很快就会明白了
And soon you will understand.
八岁时  我亲眼看着父母被烧死
I was 8 years old when I watched my parents burn.
火刑是消灭巫师亘古不变的方法
Timeless solution for exterminating witches.
你知道那是什么感觉吗
Do you know what it's like
眼睁睁看着
To witness the death of those you love
你最爱的人死去
More than anyone else in the world?
我无法想象
I can't imagine.
那能让你意识到自己的能力
It teaches you what you are capable of.
那种深埋体内  你也许永远不会察觉的能力
The depths and limits you never knew you had.
然而  即便他们已被挫骨扬灰
And, yet, even as their ashes lingered in the air,
我却幸免于难
Steps were taken to spare me a similar fate.
我被赶出英格兰  漂洋过海
So I was whisked from England, sent across the sea,
在瘟疫和鼠疫中幸存下来
surviving plague and pestilence,
来到了这个新世界
to the new world.
我被忠诚的巫师信徒收养
I was taken in by those loyal to the cause
他们养育我长大  并教会我两件事
who raised me with a twin mission...
一是如何发掘出自身的能力
Teach me to harness the power of who I was
同时隐藏这种能力不被世人所知
And yet to keep it hidden from the world.
后来  我有了自己的家庭
And then I was raising a family of my own
深知我最珍爱的两个人
knowing that those I held most precious
恰恰被我自己所危及着
live in every bit the jeopardy that I do.
我是巫师吗
Am I a witch?
是
Yes.
但那会减少丝毫我对你的父爱吗
But does that make me any less of a loving father?
不会
No.
绝对不会
Most certainly not.
进来
Enter.
您一召唤我就来了
I came as soon as you summoned me.
您好像不太高兴
I suspect you're not pleased.
怎么回事  西布里夫人
What happened, Mrs. Sibley?
哦  这个啊
Oh, uh, this.
我还一直在自欺欺人
And here my own vanity convinced me
以为不会有人注意到呢
it was hardly noticeable.
陪我喝杯茶吧
Join me in tea,
让我跟你讲讲我的悲惨遭遇
and I will tell you my sad tale.
我去了树林
I went to the woods,
想整理一下思绪  最近的麻烦太多了
hoping to clear my mind after recent troubling events.
要糖吗
Sugar?
不用  谢谢
No, thank you.
我沉浸在自己的世界里  没注意到她
Lost in my own thoughts, I scarcely noticed her.
喝吧  艾萨克
Drink, Isaac.
直到她扑到了我身上
Until she was upon me.
谁
Who?
梅西·路易丝
Mercy Lewis,
她没有因为我曾经收留过她
who greeted me not with kindness
而心怀感恩
for once taking her in...
却向我回报以暴力和愤怒
But with violence and anger.
缇图芭被指控  她认为我难逃其咎
She finds me guilty for Tituba's accusations.
仿佛我还得对自己女仆的想法负责似的
as if I'm responsible for my servant's mind.
西布里夫人
Mrs. Sibley?
怎么  艾萨克
Yes, Isaac?
这茶
The tea.
怎么了
What about it?
让你周身发热了吗  还是觉得很困
Is it making you warm or just sleepy?
都有
Both.
很好  那说明有用了
Good. Then it's working.
我不介意告诉你实话
I don't mind telling you this
因为等你醒了就什么都不记得了
Because when you wake, you'll remember nothing.
不过我确实抱歉要这样利用你
Although I do regret using you like this.
即便在塞勒姆  也还有像你这样的好人
Even in Salem, there are those who deserve better.
但英克里斯深知你胆小本分
But Increase knows that you're far too scared and guileless
不可能再次骗他
to betray him again.
他会相信你的话
He will take your words as fact.
我的话
Words?
你听说梅西在附近出没
That hearing that Mercy lurked nearby,
于是去树林里找她
you sought her in the woods.
但她动作太快  被她逃脱了
But she was too quick, and she evaded you.
英克里斯会仔细分析你每一句话
Increase will parse your words
直到他相信你说的是实话
until he is convinced they are truth.
跟我重复一遍  艾萨克
So repeat after me, Isaac.
"我去丛林里"
"I went to the woods..."
I went to the woods...
"为了找梅西·路易丝"
"...to find Mercy Lewis."
...to find Mercy Lewis.
"穿过小河  在低垂的树枝旁  我发现了她"
"Past the lake, beside the weeping tree, I spied her."
Past the lake, beside the weeping tree, I spied her.
很好  再说一遍
Very good. Again.
我们真的了解自己身边的人吗
Can we ever truly know our neighbor,
相信他们就是看上去的那样
trust that they are whom they seem to be,
那些他们想让我们相信的形象
who they would have us believe them to be?
有人说某个年轻女子  小姑娘
We are told that a young woman, a girl,
被当做巫师的工具  不料却发现她
really was a tool of the witches only to find that she is,
实际上就是巫师本人
in fact, a witch herself.
如今  塞勒姆先驱者之子也被控以同样罪名
And now Salem's first son stands likewise accused.
看看周围
Look around.
看看你的左右
Look to either side.
看看你身旁的人
Look to your neighbor.
扪心自问
And ask yourself,
他们是朋友还是男巫
"Friend or sorcerer?
是妻子还是女巫
Wife or witch?"
是上帝还是魔鬼
God or devil!
谁说的  出来
Who said that? Show yourself.
是我儿子啊
It is my son.
不用理睬他
Pay him no mind.
别用你们的宽容放纵他
Do not reward him with your indulgence.
你以上帝之名问着
You question who the people of Salem are
塞勒姆的民众都是谁
in the name of god.
然后呢
Yes?
但是塞勒姆的民众该不该也问问你是谁
But should the people of Salem not question who you are?
因为魔鬼也会反其道而行
For how else would the devil appear...
以上帝之名出现
but in the cloak of the lord?
出去
Get out.
你喝醉了
You are drunk!
你的大喊大叫只会给自己蒙羞
Your rantings only serve to embarrass yourself.
现在出去
Remove yourself now.
还不走
You will not?
我亲自送你走
I will remove you myself!
指认自己的父亲
Point the finger at her own father?
她绝不会的
She would never.
你肯定吗
Are you certain of that?
昨晚我才发现她和英克里斯在一起呢
Wasn't it just last night that I found her with Increase?
她没有这个企图
She had no intention.
就是装装样子
She was simply acting out.
塞勒姆有一堆装腔作势的人
Salem is filled with those who act out --
朋友装成敌人
friends who act like enemies,
敌人装成判决者
enemies who act as executioners.
这些对她来说都太陌生
This is all new to her.
放心吧  她会慢慢接受的
Trust that, in time, she will accept it.
是啊  但要是没接受  又怎么办
Yes, and if not, what then?
那就是时候告诉她剩下的故事了
Then it may be time to tell her the rest of the story.
恐怕现在已经是时候了
I'm afraid that time has already come.
你的故事很是引人入胜
Your story is really quite fantastic.
玛丽·西布里被梅西·路易丝攻击了
Mary Sibley attacked by Mercy Lewis.
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
出于对玛丽的忠诚
And out of loyalty to Mary,
你追踪那个姑娘进了丛林
you followed the girl into the woods.
对玛丽的忠诚
Loyalty to Mary?
不是的  先生  是对您的忠诚
No, sir. Loyalty to you.
对我
Me?
您不是急着想找那个姑娘吗
Are you not eager to find the girl?
您不是告诉我
Did you not tell me
要替您眼观四路耳听八方吗
to keep my eyes and ears open on your behalf?
所以当我得知她出没在丛林边缘时
So when I learned she lurked at the wood's edge,
我就遵照您的意图去寻找她了
I sought her out, as I knew you would have wanted.
这叫刺挠
This is called a cilice.
我穿着它来时刻提醒自己所犯下的罪恶
I wear this to remind myself of my own failing.
你是否很惊讶  艾萨克
Does it surprise you, Isaac,
当你听到即使是我也身负罪恶
to learn that even I have sins I must atone for?
你犯过罪吗
Have you ever sinned?
有也不是故意的  先生
Not intentionally, sir.
你现在在犯罪吗
Are you sinning now?
你是否在骗我
Are you lying to me?
我说的是实话  牧师
I speak the truth, reverend.
我看见她了  但是没法抓住她
I saw her, but could not catch her.
你还记得最后一次看见梅西是在哪儿吗
And can you recall where it was you last laid eyes on Mercy?
穿过小河  在低垂的树枝旁  我发现了她
Past the lake, beside the weeping tree, I spied her.
你能带我去那儿吗
And you could -- you could lead me there?
是的  当然了  先生
Yes, of course, sir.
那么
Well, then.
收拾一下吧  小伙子
prepare yourself, my boy.
我们两个
For you and I...
要去猎捕巫师了
are going witch hunting.
霍尔小姐
Miss Hale.
是不是打扰到你了  牧师
Am I intruding, reverend?
我正准备享用我的下午"茶"
Well, I was just about to enjoy my late-afternoon drink.
可别把这跟我的晚"茶"弄混了
Not to be confused, of course, with my early-evening drink,
不过也差不多是时候了
which I anticipate taking place shortly, as well.
你也来一杯吗
Perhaps?
不用  谢谢  我不能久留
Oh, no, thank you. I can not stay.
我只是来说一声  我很抱歉
I simply came to say... I'm sorry.
为了什么
For?
所有事
Everything.
我没有好好对待你
I have not treated you well...
也不完全公平
nor entirely fairly.
所以说我父亲的所为让你觉得我很可怜  是吗
So my father has earned me your pity. Is that right?
不
No.
我只是看到了我们的相似之处
I simply see that we are alike.
都有一个心机深沉的父亲
Both children of complicated men.
霍尔治安官  心机深沉吗
Magistrate Hale, complicated?
说实话  我总觉得他就是个
In truth, he's always seemed a bit of a...
单纯的白痴
a simpleton to me.
不  我向你保证
No, I assure you.
他和塞勒姆中的人一样充满心机
He is as complex as any man in Salem.
听说你对巫师颇有研究啊
You have made quite a study of them -- witches.
即便如此  我仍觉得自己对他们一无所知
For all my studies, I'm not sure I truly know a thing.
我可不这么认为
Oh, I doubt that.
你一定能告诉我许多关于他们的事情
I'm sure you could tell me all about them.
我还不知道你也相信巫师的存在
I did not know you even believed in witches.
我改变了想法
I've had a change of heart.
为什么呢
And why is that?
也许是我一直都对其有兴趣
Perhaps it is an interest I've lived with my entire life,
但是直到最近才发现
but wasn't aware of until recently.
好吧
Well, um...
如果你有时间  就请坐吧
If you have a moment, please sit,
我会告诉你关于巫师的一切
and I will tell you all about witches.
就是这  牧师
It's here, reverend.
你确定吗
You're sure?
这就是那条通往她藏身之处的小路
It was the trail I took that led me to her.
小心点  先生
Careful, sir.
我们得提防她的突然袭击
We do not know when she could strike.
告诉我  你真的独自一人
Tell me, did you really travel
走进丛林深处
this deep into the woods alone
只为了找到那个女孩吗
to find the girl?
为了你  先生
For you, sir.
为了我
For me?
我很感动
I'm touched.
但我却仍然无法相信你
I'm also extremely skeptical.
牧师
Reverend?
你到底有何意图
What is your plan?
意图
Plan?
引我来此  好对我下手吗
To lure me? To kill me?
不  我为什么要这么做
No. Why would I? How?
或者说
Or perhaps
或者你别无选择
perhaps you did not have a choice.
告诉我  你在为谁卖命
Tell me, whose bidding is it that you do?
是约翰·奥登想让我死吗
Is it John Alden who wants me dead?
还是玛丽·西布里
Or Mary Sibley?
又或者他俩同流合污
Or do they work in concert?
马上告诉我  不然我就顺脖一刀
Tell me now or I'll slide this blade along your throat
在我擦血入鞘之前你就会早已死透
and you'll be dead before I clean and sheath it.
牧师  我发誓这么做都是为了您
Reverend, I promise you I'm here on your behalf
绝无二心
and yours alone.
先生
Sir!
追上她  快去
After her! Go on!
你曾亲眼见过她们
You've seen one?
我是说  一个女巫
A witch, I mean?
是的
I have.
这恶毒的老怪物多年来一直未被人识破
A vile creature who walked undetected for years
幸好最终  她终究暴露了本性
until finally her true nature was revealed.
就是说她们藏在我们之中吗
So they hide amongst us?
这想法改变的真彻底
This change of heart is remarkable.
真不懂为什么我花了这么久才明白
Remarkable that it took so long.
生活在塞勒姆却不相信有巫师
Living in Salem and not believing in witches
就如同生活在伦敦却不相信有大雾一般
is like living in london and not believing in fog.
我居然傻到去否认摆在眼前的事实
It is to deny what is right in front of you.
你父亲怎么看待你这种转变
And what does your father think of your conversion?
我父亲
My father...
他正是
above all is...
转变我看法的原因
responsible for it.
或许他真如你说的一样心机深沉
Perhaps he's as complicated as you say.
但是我父亲没有说明的是
But what my father did not answer is...
巫师们想要什么
what do witches want?
有人说他们只想与我们和平共处
Some say they want only to live in peace.
其他人  譬如我父亲
Others, like my father,
说他们的目的只有一个
say that they desire nothing less
那就是将人类彻底灭绝
than the destruction of all mankind.
如果你父亲是正确的呢
And is your father correct?
我父亲大多数时候都是正确的
My father's correct in most matters.
他对你的看法也是正确的吗
Is he correct about you?
我父亲认为我是个废物
My father thinks I'm a failure.
因为我既不虔诚  还终日酗酒
Since I have failed at both piety and sobriety.
没错
Yes.
我想这两点大家都有目共睹
The evidence supports his case.
他错了
He's wrong.
如今我的失败又加上了一件
Another failure to add to my list.
你唯一的失败就是没有成为你的父亲
Your only failure is not becoming your father.
而那根本不算失败
And that is no failure.
[咒语]
Terra sunt carnes et ossa.
Domini est terra et ossa.
[咒语]
Terra sunt carnes et ossa.
Domini est terra et ossa.
我没看到她
I do not see her.
不用担心  她会回来的
Fear not. She will return.
要不她还怎么杀掉我呢
For how else can she attempt to kill me?
[咒语]
Domini est terra et ossa.
撒旦是个强大的敌人
Satan is a formidable enemy
不是因为他的邪恶  而是因为他很狡猾
not because he's evil, but because he is sly.
我们俩是老相识了
Oh, we know each other well.
[咒语]
Et nos unum benedictus.
牧师
Reverend?
先生
Sir?
先生  麦哲牧师
Sir? Reverend Mather?
在找我吗  牧师
Looking for me, reverend?
我会将你抓回塞勒姆
You will return with me to Salem,
你会受到审判的  巫师
and you will stand trial, witch.
我可不这么认为
I don't think so.
难道你真的以为
Did you think it would only take
仅凭一把小刀便能杀了我吗  牧师
one knife to kill me, reverend?
快追上去
After her!
艾萨克  别让她跑了
Isaac, don't let her get away!
艾萨克
Isaac!
梅西的武器
Mercy's weapon.
可怜的孩子
Oh, my poor boy.
别用力呼吸
Breathe shallow.
有我陪着你
You are not alone.
什么事
Yes?
麦哲牧师让您去他那一趟
Reverend Mather has requested you in his quarters.
柯顿吗
Cotton?
不  夫人
Uh, no, ma'am.
是英克里斯
Increase.
西布里夫人
Mrs. Sibley,
这边请
this way.
能让我单独跟他待一阵吗
May I have a moment with him?
艾萨克
Isaac.
亲爱的艾萨克
Oh, sweet isaac.
我从未想过你会因此而受伤
I never intended for you to meet this fate.
我向你保证
So I promise you --
尽管塞勒姆即将迎来腥风血雨
though a grim future awaits the people of Salem --
但我不会让你再受到任何伤害
I will protect you from any further pain.
我向你保证
I swear to you.
我们出去吧
Come now.
他需要休息
He needs his rest.
牧师  我不明白
Reverend, I am at a loss.
为什么艾萨克会独自一人去寻找梅西
why Isaac would take it upon himself to seek out mercy...
我也问了他同样的问题
I asked him the same question.
他怎么说
And what did he say?
他说是为了我
He said he did it on my behalf,
但我却无法相信
which I find very odd
因为我很清楚  他十分憎恨我
when you consider the fact that he detests me.
憎恨您
Detests you?
不  艾萨克不会恨任何人
No. No, isaac hates no one.
他做不到
He is incapable of it.
那至少你应该同意
Well, at least you will agree his mind is...
他就像个小孩
childlike.
正因如此
And, like a child,
他会听从别人的意识和想法
he absorbs the thoughts and the intents of others.
什么别人
What others?
那些真正恨我的
Someone who does hate me...
想我死的人
and desires me...dead.
还有一件事  牧师
And one other matter, reverend --
我对约翰·奥登是巫师一事仍心存怀疑
I remain skeptical that John Alden is a witch.
如果不是奥登
Ah, if not Alden,
那告诉我  到底是谁
tell me who, then, is responsible
导致了塞勒姆发生的一切
for what has transpired in Salem?
很可惜  我不知道
Regrettably, I do not know.
或许我们可以一起祈祷
Well, perhaps we can hope together
那个真正有罪的人能站出来
that the truly guilty party will step forward
洗脱上尉的罪名
and...exonerate the good captain.
你觉得这有可能吗  玛丽
Do you think that's a possibility, Mary?
这里是塞勒姆
This is Salem.
凡事皆有可能
I think there are no limits to what is possible.
你又是来冲我发脾气的吗
Am I to expect another outburst?
不
No.
我已经几个小时没沾酒了
I've not had a drink for hours.
真不敢相信你居然认为这也算进步
Amazing what one comes to accept as a sign of progress.
你这个时候来做什么
Why have you come at this hour?
我一直在考虑您的提议
I've been contemplating your offer.
参与奥登上尉的审判
To join you in the prosecution of captain Alden.
你终于想清楚我说的好处了
And you have seen the wisdom in it?
我确实明白了
I have seen wisdom...
但不是您说的那些
But not yours.
我决定为奥登上尉辩护
I've decided to defend captain Alden.
为他辩护
To defend?
你知道我有多骄傲吗
Oh, imagine how proud I am to have...
看着我亲手养育的儿子
raised a son so steadfast in his ability
总是如此坚定地做出错误的决定
to consistently make the wrong decision.
安
Anne.
明天再说吧  父亲  我该睡了
Please, father, it's far past my bedtime.
我只要一小会
I only require a moment.
有些事我一直没有告诉你
Something I neglected to tell you before...
是关于那个面具的
regarding that mask.
这事能晚点再说吗
Truly, can this wait?
不能再等了
It has waited long enough.
是这样的
And it is this
那个面具的能力
that the power of that mask
只能被一种人所激活
can only be accessed by those of one kind.
哪种人
And what kind is that?
跟我一样的人
My kind.
但我激活了...
But it worked when I...
你是说我是...
are you saying that I am...
跟我一样
like me.
是个巫师
A witch.